influence.co 2019-04-01

# Influence.co | Privacy Policy

Effective as of March 5, 2019                                                                                                                                                        

This Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand how Marmont, Inc. (“ **Marmont** ”, “ **Influence.co** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **us** ” or “ **our** ”) collects, uses and shares personal information.

**Table of Contents**

·       **Privacy Policy**

·       **Personal Information We Collect**

·       **How We Use Your Personal Information**

·       **How We Share your Personal Information**

·       **Your Choices**

·       **Other Important Privacy Information**

·       **How to Contact Us**

·       **Notice to European Users**

·       **Cookie Policy**

This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, share, and otherwise process personal information your personal information and explains the rights and choices available to individuals with respect to their information.  This Privacy Policy applies if you visit our websites at Influence.co, blog.Influence.co or any other website to which we post this privacy policy (the “ **Sites** ”); use our services through a customer administrator account; or receive our communications.  For convenience, we refer to the Sites and our services collectively as the “ **Service** ”. Please note that we may provide additional or supplemental privacy notices to individuals at the time we collect their data.

We provide services that businesses use to connect individuals, businesses and agencies in the marketing industry for the express, but not limited purposes of working on influencer marketing projects.  This Privacy Policy does not apply to any information collected, used or shared by our customers or that we handle on our customers’ behalf.  Our customers have their own policies for how they handle personal information, and our contracts with our customers restrict how we use information that we handle on their behalf.  You should contact the relevant customer if you have questions, concerns or requests regarding personal information that the customer handles or that we handle on its behalf.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to [add description (e.g., interactions outside of website/app, etc.)].

Individuals located in the European Union should be sure to review the important information provided here in addition to the other provisions of this Privacy Policy.

## Information you give us.  Personal information you may provide through the Service or otherwise communicate to us includes:

·      **Contact information.**   When you create an account, use the Service, or contact us through the Sites, we may collect information such as your first and last name, email and mailing addresses, phone number, professional title and company name. 

·      **User generated content.** We may collect content or other information that you provide or create when you interact with the Service, such as text from the messaging functionality on our site, text, images and video from your profile, including images to decorate your profile page, biographical data, references to business associates or external blogs or publications, and text from the use of the live chat functionality on our site. 

·      **Events information.**   If you register for or participate in one of our meetings or events, we may collect the information you provide to us related to or through the event. 

·      **Feedback or Correspondence.**   We may collect information about you that you provide when you request information from us, interact with us by email, on phone calls, the use of live chat functionality, or through other methods of communication, such as posting public comments, or otherwise correspond with us.

·       **Application Information.**  This may include information about grant applicants, job applicants, and similar individuals, such as professional credentials, educational and work history, present and past institutional affiliations, publications, research interests, areas of professional focus or specialization, and other information of the type typically included on a resume, curriculum vitae, or scientific research grant application. ****

·       **Demographic Information.** Information such as your zip code, gender, date of birth, age and/or income.

·       **Profile information.** Information such as your username and password that you may set to establish an online account with us, a short biography, your photograph, interests and preferences, and social media profile and account information, including the number of followers, comments, and likes your profiles receive.

·       **Financial information.** When you use the Service we may collect payment information about you or your organization, such as tax identification number, bank account information or payment card information.

·       **Transaction information.** Information including details about payments to and from you and other details of products or services you have purchased from us.

·       **Usage information. I** nformation about how you use our websites and interact with us, including information associated with any content you upload to the websites or otherwise submit to us, and information you provide when you use any interactive features of the websites

·       **Subscription information.** This includes information such your preferences for receiving communications about our activities, events, and publications, and details about how you engage with our communications.

·      **Other information.**   We may collect other information about you that is not specifically listed here and will use it in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## Information automatically collected.  Our servers and third party service providers may automatically record certain information about how you use the Service and the computers or devices you use to access the Service, such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address, domain name, device and browser type, operating system, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, the website you visited before browsing to our websites, general location information such as city, state or geographic area; and information about the pages or features of the Service that you browse and the time you spend on those pages or features, the times and frequency with which you use the Service, the links that you click on or use and other statistics.  We collect this information in server logs and by using cookies, web beacons and similar tracking technologies. See our Cookie Policy for more information.

**Information we get from others.   **We may receive personal information about you or your company from third parties (e.g., joint marketing partners or social media platforms, your employer, publicly available sources, analytics or data providers, professional recruiters, or researchers).  We may add this information to the information we have already collected from you and will handle it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

**Sensitive personal information.**   We do not intentionally collect any sensitive personal information (e.g., social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin; political opinions, religion or other beliefs; health, biometrics or genetic characteristics; criminal background or union membership) through the Service or otherwise, but if you provide it to us, you must consent to our use of this information as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not consent to our processing and use of such sensitive personal information, you must not submit such sensitive personal information to us.

We use your personal information for the following purposes and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy or at the time of collection:

## To operate the Service.  We use your personal information:

·       to provide, operate and improve the Service;

·       to communicate with you about the Service, including by sending you announcements, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;

·       to communicate with you about events or contests in which you participate;

·       to facilitate communication with other site users such as brands, agencies, or influencers;

·       to understand your needs and interests, and personalize your experience with the Service; and

·       to respond to your requests, questions and feedback related to the Service.

## For research and development.  We analyze use of the Service to study trends and users’ movements around the Service, gather demographic information about our user base, improve the Service and develop new products and services.

**To manage events.**   We use your contact details and other personal information to plan and host events or webinars for which you have registered or that you attend, including sending related communications to you.

## To send you marketing and promotional communications.  We may send you promotions, newsletters or other marketing communications, but you may opt out of receiving them as described in the Opt out of marketing section below.

## To create anonymous data.  We may create aggregated and other anonymous data from our users’ information.  We make personal information into anonymous data by removing information that makes the data personally identifiable.  We may use this anonymous data and share it with third parties to understand and improve the Service, promote our business and for other lawful business purposes. 

## For compliance, fraud prevention and safety.  We may use your personal information and share it with government officials, law enforcement or private parties, as we believe appropriate to:

## ·       protect our, your or others’ rights, privacy, safety or property (including by making and defending legal claims);

## ·       enforce the terms and conditions that govern the Service; 

## ·       protect, investigate and deter against fraudulent, harmful, unauthorized, unethical or illegal activity;

## ·       comply with applicable laws, lawful requests and legal process, such as to respond to subpoenas or requests from government authorities; and

## ·       where permitted by law in connection with a legal investigation.

## With your consent.  In some cases we may specifically ask for your consent to collect, use or share your personal information, such as when required by law. 

We do not share your personal information with third parties without your consent, except in the following circumstances or as described in this Privacy Policy:

**Affiliates.   **We may share your personal information with parent companies, subsidiaries and affiliates for use consistent with this Privacy Policy.

**Service providers.**  We may share your personal information with third party companies and individuals as needed for them to provide us with services that help us provide the Service or support our business activities (such as website analytics, email delivery, marketing/advertising, IT providers, technical support, and legal and other professional advice).  We authorize these third parties to access your personal information to the extent reasonably necessary for them to provide their services and in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy, and these third parties are prohibited from using or disclosing your information for any other purpose.

**Third Party Payment Processing.**  For online payments and/or Automated Clearing House (ACH) payouts, we use the payment services of [Stripe](https://stripe.com/). We do not process, record or maintain your credit card or bank account information and we will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds. For more information on how payments are handled, or to understand the data security and privacy afforded such information, please refer to Stripes’ [Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/US/PRIVACY).

**Third-Party Interactions.** Certain functionality of the Service may permit interactions that you initiate between the Service and a third party website or service (“Third Party Interactions”). Examples of Third Party Interactions may include technology that enables you to “like” or “share” content from the Service on or to other websites or services; to transmit content to the Service from your account on a third party website or service; to otherwise connect the Service to a third party website or service, such as through an application programming interface (API) made available by us or a third party; or for users to register for an account and login through social networking sites such as Facebook and Google (each an “SNS”). By registering or logging in through a SNS, you are allowing the Service to access your information and you are agreeing to the SNS’s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy in your use of such services. We may receive information from the SNS to make it easier for you to create an account with us. Any information that we collect from your SNS account may depend on the privacy settings you have with that SNS, so please consult the SNS’s privacy and data practices. ****

If you choose to use Third Party Interactions, information you post or provide access to may be publicly displayed on the Service or by the provider of the social feature that you use. Similarly, if you post information on a third party platform that references the Service (e.g., by mentioning one of the Service or using a hashtag associated with the Service in a tweet or status update), your post may be published on our Sites in accordance with the terms of the third party website or service. Also, both we and the third party may have access to certain information about you and your use of the Service and the third party website or service. In addition, we may receive information about you in connection with other users’ use of Third Party Interactions (e.g., we may learn that you are a “friend” or “connection” of the third party or receive other information about you that the other user enables us to receive).

The information we collect in connection with Third Party Interactions is subject to this Privacy Policy. The information collected and stored by the third party remains subject to the third party’s privacy practices, including whether the third party continues to share information with us, the types of information shared, and your choices with regard to what is visible to others on that third party website or service.

**Community Features.** The Service may provide you the opportunity to participate and post User Content publicly through reviews, surveys, interactive features, or other communication functionality (“Community Features”). We may provide functionality for you to submit or post User Content through Community Features, by linking the Service to a third party service, or otherwise. Please note that certain information, such as your name, may be publicly displayed on the Service along with your User Content. User Content consisting of uploaded files may contain metadata, which may contain Personal Information or other information about or relating to you. You may wish to remove metadata from your files before transmitting such files to us. **_Note that anything you post through Community Features is public – others will have access to your User Content and may use it or share it with third parties. If you choose to voluntarily disclose Personal Information, that information will be considered public information and the protections of this Privacy Policy will not apply. If you submit User Content, it may be published online or offline at any time. In addition, we may use your User Content and any excerpt from your User Content in connection with our advertising, marketing, publicity and promotional activities. Note also that publicly posted information may be indexed on search provider and other websites. As outlined in the_ Third party sites and services _section below, we do not control third party websites, applications or services, and are not responsible for their actions._**

**Professional advisors.** We may disclose your personal information to professional advisors, such as lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers, where necessary in the course of the professional services that they render to us.

**For compliance, fraud prevention and safety.** We may share your personal information for the compliance, fraud prevention and safety purposes described above.  

**Business transfers.**   We may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of our business or assets, including your personal information, in connection with a business deal (or potential business deal) such as a corporate divestiture, merger, consolidation, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, or in the event of bankruptcy or dissolution. In such a case, we will make reasonable efforts to require the recipient to honor this Privacy Policy.

In this section, we describe the rights and choices available to all users. Users who are located within the European Union can find additional information about their rights below.

## Access, Update, Correct or Delete Your Information. If you have registered for an account with us, you may review, update, correct, or delete the personal information in your account profile by logging into your account or by contacting us at [support@influence.co](mailto:support@influence.co).

## Opt out of marketing.  You may opt out of marketing-related emails by following the unsubscribe instructions in the email or by logging into your account and updating your preferences in the account settings.  You may continue to receive Service-related and other non-marketing emails.  Opting out of emails or other communications related to contests or promotions may terminate your eligibility to participate in those contests or promotions.  Be sure to check the relevant contest or promotion rules before you opt out.

## Cookies.  We may allow service providers and other third parties to use cookies and similar technologies to track your browsing activity over time and across the Service and third party websites.  For more details, see our Cookie Policy. 

## Targeted online advertising. Some of the business partners that collect information about users’ activities of the Service may be members of organizations or programs that provide choices to individuals regarding the use of their browsing behavior or mobile application usage for purposes of targeted advertising. 

Users may opt out of receiving targeted advertising on websites through members of the Network Advertising Initiative by clicking [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) or the Digital Advertising Alliance by clicking [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices). European users may opt out of receiving targeted advertising on websites through members of the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance by clicking [here](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/), selecting the user’s country, and then clicking “Choices” (or similarly titled link). Please note that we also may work with companies that offer their own opt-out mechanisms and may not participate in the opt-out mechanisms that we linked above.

If you choose to opt-out of targeted advertisements, you will still see advertisements online but they may not be relevant to you. Even if you do choose to opt out, not all companies that serve online behavioral advertising are included in this list, and so you may still receive some cookies and tailored advertisements from companies that are not listed.

## Do Not Track.  Some Internet browsers may be configured to send “Do Not Track” signals to the online services that you visit.  We currently do not respond to “Do Not Track” or similar signals.  To find out more about “Do Not Track,” please visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

## Choosing not to share your personal information. Where we are required by law to collect your personal information, or where we need your personal information in order to provide the Service to you, if you do not provide this information when requested (or you later ask to delete it), we may not be able to provide you with our services.  We will tell you what information you must provide to receive the Service by designating it as required in the Service or on the Sites or through other appropriate means.

## De-Linking Third Party Interactions and SNS. The Service enables you to interact with or post content to certain third parties and SNSs. If you would like to discontinue these interactions and connections, please refer to the privacy settings of the third party or SNS to determine how you may adjust our permissions and manage the interactivity between the Services and your social media account.

## Third party sites and services.  The Service may contain links to other websites and services operated by third parties.  These links are not an endorsement of, or representation that we are affiliated with, any third party.  We do not control third party websites, applications or services, and are not responsible for their actions.  Other websites and services follow different rules regarding their collection, use and sharing of your personal information.  We encourage you to read their privacy policies to learn more.

In addition, our content may be included on web pages and websites that are not associated with us and over which we have no control. These third parties may collect data through the use of their own cookies, pixel tags or other technology, independently collect information or solicit Personal Information, and may have the ability to track your use of their websites and services. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any third party.

## Security practices.  The security of your personal information is important to us.  We employ a number of organizational, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information we collect.  However, security risk is inherent in all internet and information technologies and we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information.  If you have a user account for the Service, you are solely responsible for maintaining and protecting the confidentiality of your account username, password and other account information in your possession.

**International data use.**   We are headquartered in the United States and have affiliates and service providers in other countries, and your personal information may be collected, used and stored in the United States or other locations outside of your home country.  Privacy laws in the locations where we handle your personal information may not be as protective as the privacy laws in your home country. 

European Union users should read the important information provided below about transfer of personal information outside of the European Union. 

## Children.  The Service is not directed at, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from, anyone under the age of 16.  If we learn that personal information of someone under the age of 16 has been submitted to us, we will take appropriate steps to delete it. 

**Customer-administered accounts.   **Where the Service is provided to you through your employer or another organization, that organization is the administrator of the Service.  We are not responsible for the privacy or security practices of these organizations, which have their own privacy policies.  Please note that your organization’s administrator may be able to: ****

·       require you to reset your account password;

·       restrict, suspend or terminate your access to the Service;

·       access information in and about your account;

·       access or retain information stored as part of your account;

·       change the email address associated with your account;

·       change your information, including profile information; and

·       restrict your ability to edit, restrict, modify or delete information.

Please contact your organization or refer to your administrator’s organizational policies for more information.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**.  We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. If we make changes to this Privacy Policy, we will post them on the Sites and indicate the effective date of the change.  If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by updating the date of this Privacy Policy and posting it on the Sites. We may (and, where required by law, will) also provide notification of changes in another way that we believe is reasonably likely to reach you, such as via e-mail (if you have an account where we have your contact information) or another manner through the Site. We encourage you to periodically review our Privacy Policy to stay informed about how we collect, use, share, and otherwise process personal information.

Please direct any questions or comments about this Policy to:

Influence.co

511 Mountain View Road

Boulder, CO 80302 

The following applies to individuals in the European Economic Area and the United Kingdom.

## Personal information. References to “personal information” in this Privacy Policy are equivalent to “personal data” governed by European data protection legislation. 

## Controller.  Marmont, Inc. is the controller of your personal information covered by this Privacy Policy for purposes of European data protection legislation. 

## Legal bases for processing.  Our legal basis for processing the personal information described in this Privacy Policy will depend on the type of personal information and the specific context in which we process it.  However, the legal bases we typically rely on are set out in the table below.  If you have questions about the legal basis of how we process your personal information, contact us at [support@influence.co](mailto:support@influence.co).

**Processing purpose** (click link for details) ****

| 

**Legal basis**  
  
---|---  
  
To operate the Service  

| 

You have entered a contract with us for the provision of the Service and we need to process your personal information to provide services you have requested or take steps that you request prior to providing services.  If we have not entered into a contract with you, we process your personal information based on our legitimate interest in providing the Service you access and request.   
  
To administer events and contests

For research and development

To send you marketing communications

To create anonymous data

For compliance, fraud prevention and safety  

| 

These activities constitute our legitimate interests.  We do not use your personal information for these activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law).  
  
For compliance, fraud prevention and safety

| 

Processing is necessary to comply with our legal obligations.  
  
With your consent

| 

Processing is based on your consent.  Where we rely on your consent you have the right to withdraw it anytime in the manner indicated when you consent or in the Service.   
  
To share your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy

| 

This sharing constitutes our legitimate interests, and in some cases may be necessary to comply with our legal obligations.  
  
## Use for new purposes

## We may use your personal information for reasons not described in this Privacy Policy where permitted by law and the reason is compatible with the purpose for which we collected it.  If we need to use your personal information for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and explain the applicable legal basis. 

## Retention

## We retain personal information where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested; to comply with applicable contractual, legal, tax or accounting requirements; to establish or defend legal claims; or for fraud prevention).  To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal information, the purposes for which we process your personal information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible. In some circumstances we may anonymize your personal information (so that it can no longer be associated with you), in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

## Your rights

European data protection laws give you certain rights regarding your personal information.  You may ask us to take the following actions in relation to your personal information that we hold:

·       **Access.**   Provide you with information about our processing of your personal information and give you access to your personal information.

·       **Correct.**   Update or correct inaccuracies in your personal information.

·       **Delete.**   Delete your personal information.

·       **Transfer.**   Transfer a machine-readable copy of your personal information to you or a third party of your choice.

·       **Restrict.**   Restrict the processing of your personal information.

·       **Object.**   Object to our reliance on our legitimate interests as the basis of our processing of your personal information that impacts your rights. 

You may submit these requests by email to [support@influence.co](mailto:support@influence.co) or our postal address provided above.  We may request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and process your request.  Applicable law may require or permit us to decline your request.  If we decline your request, we will tell you why, subject to legal restrictions.  If you would like to submit a complaint about our use of your personal information or our response to your requests regarding your personal information, you may contact us or submit a complaint to the data protection regulator in your jurisdiction.  You can find your data protection regulator [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm). 

## Cross-Border Data Transfer

If we transfer your personal information from the European Economic Area to a country outside of it and are required to apply additional safeguards to your personal information under European data protection legislation, we will do so, for instance, by entering into standard contractual clauses for the transfer of data as approved by the European Commission.  Please contact us for further information about any such transfers and the safeguards applied.
